# José Juan Isaac Taveras Lopez

Phone: (787) 397-0643 E-mail: josejuanisaac@gmail.com

## **Summary**

Software engineer with 10+ years of experience in database design & maintenance, data analytics & visualizations, fullstack web development, and network security analysis. Proven ability to to conduct research in order to produce reports that directly drive organization goals and improve operational processes.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Assistant Manager at Domino's Pizza, Winchester, Virginia

- From March 2022 to August 2022
- Counted full inventory daily in order to ascertain relevant information for product resupply orders which
  occurred 3 times a week,
- Learned to manage and supervise each store section: makeline, driver dispatch, backend office,
- Closed and opened store on a weekly basis, ensuring till count and daily deposits are completed accurately
  and successfully,
- Dealt with customer complaints and follow ups in order to maintain store's good standing.

#### Delivery Expert at Domino's Pizza, Winchester, Virginia

- From January 2022 to March 2022
- Completed order delivery requests, ensuring all items are accounted for and pizza ingredients match order,
- Contributed to the good working order of the store by learning all store section tasks.

#### Target Digital Network Analyst at U.S. Army, Fort Meade, Maryland

- From 2019 to December 2021,
- Conducted target development such as open-source research and signals analysis,
- Authored and contributed to publishing several reports used by federal organizations,
- Maintained and organized documentation of collected data for presentations,
- Used network analysis tools to produce pattern-of-life visualizations,
- Collaborated in a joint military environment by developing knowledge management and project communication strategies to overcome workspace restrictions imposed by COVID-19,
- Developed browser-based tools to visualize and edit structured data sets (JSON, CSV).

## Business Intelligence Developer as Wovenware, San Juan, Puerto Rico

- From 2014 up to 2017, stepped away for 10 months between 2015 and 2016 conducting web development bootcamp,
- Produced descriptive analytics to display aggregate user information using Qlikview BI software,
- Designed query scripts while verifying the data that was produced matched expected results,
- Performed maintenance and optimization on Qlikview backend server.

#### Rubric Solution, Manati, Puerto Rico

- Provided project-based development from 2010 to 2015,
- Designed initial SQL ER diagram and implementation using MySQL,
- Integrated Open Source chat software into underlying system and built custom group management interface,
- Implemented payment process flow with local banking provider that used XML SOAP for secure information transfer.

### **Education**

University of Puerto Rico, Mayagüez Campus

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering (2014)

## **Training and Certifications**

- U.S. ARMY Fully Qualified as Basic Target Digital Network Analyst, Fort Meade, MD (2020)
- Army Analysis and Reporting Course, Goodfellow AFB, San Angelo, TX (2018)
- Web Development Bootcamp, DevBootcamp, San Francisco, CA (2016)

#### **Additional Skills and Proficiencies**

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Qlikview Dashboards, Excel
- Back-end: PHP, Ruby, Qlikview Script, MySQL
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, WAMP
- Languages: Native Spanish, full English, conversational French and Italian.